They had everything. She showed them more.
Mona Lisa Smile is a drama, history, romance film directed by Mike Newell.
Katherine Watson is a recent UCLA graduate hired to teach art history at
the prestigious all-female Wellesley College, in 1953.
Determined to confront the outdated mores of society and the institution that embraces them, Katherine inspires her
traditional students, including Betty and Joan, to challenge the lives they are expected to lead.
Katherine Ann Watson, played by Julia Roberts.
Betty Warren, played by Kirsten Dunst.
Joan Brandwyn, played by Julia Stiles.
Giselle Levy, played by Maggie Gyllenhaal.
Connie Baker, played by Ginnifer Goodwin.
Bill Dunbar, played by Dominic West.
Mona Lisa Smile is a 2003 American drama film produced by Revolution Studios and Columbia Pictures in association with Red Om Films Productions, directed by
Mike Newell, written by Lawrence Konner and Mark Rosenthal, and starring Julia Roberts, Kirsten Dunst, Julia Stiles, and Maggie Gyllenhaal.
The title is a reference to the Mona Lisa, the famous painting by Leonardo da Vinci, and to the song of the
same name, originally performed by Nat King Cole, which was covered by Seal for the film.
Julia Roberts received a record $25 million for her performance,
the highest ever earned by an actress at that time.
The film explores themes of massachusetts, art school,
inspiration, feminist, conservative.
The tone is emotional.